Maheshwaran R

Blockchain Developer

→ +91-8220448359 maheshwarankr.98@gmail.com /maheswaran-kr-a11a5b175 /Maheswaranx15

Education	Majors	Institute	Year	CGPA/%
B.E-CSE	Computer Science	SSMIET	2016-2020	7.9
Higher secondary	Computer science	St.Mary's hr.sec school	2018-2020	73.83
Matriculation	State-board	St.Mary's hr.sec school	2016-2018	88.42

SUMMARY_

Experienced blockchain engineer excelling in EVM-compatible blockchains with a stellar record in crafting smart contracts for NFTMarketplaces, meta transactions, NFT rentals and lending, and DeFi powerhouses like Uniswap, Pancakeswap, and Farming. Proficient in smart contract testing using the powerful Hardhat and Foundry framework with implementing OpenZeppelin standards for unparalleled security and unwavering trustworthiness.

Professional Experience

Blockchain developer | Osiz Technologies Pvt Ltd

Oct 2020 - Jul 2021

- Working as part of the Research and Development team of smart contract developer as well as Smart contract testing
- I have rich knowledge of building smart contracts and crypto currencies on various blockchain technologies.

Blockchain developer | Netobjex

Jul 2021 - Feb 2022

• Working as a part of Blockchain team and I have rich knowledge of building smart contracts on Algorand blockchain network and working on backend on trade chart development and NFT Marketplace.

Blockchain developer | Guardian Link

Feb 2022 - Jan 2023

- Working as a part of a Blockchain team and Worked on Various Blockchain Projects like NFTMarketplace with PBT enabled (Physically backed token) NFTMarketplace, NFTmarketplace with zero gas-fee, Initial coin offerings, NFT staking, NFT marketplace with SplitRoyalty.
- Openzeppelin standard like ERC721, ERC1155, ERC20, ERC712A, ERC2981, ERC1400 and Worked on Jump.trade (Asia's largetst metaverse cricket NFT gaming authenticated cricket NFTs).

Blockchain developer | Indigg - (contract)

Jan 2023 - Jul 2023

- Working with Senior blockchain team and Worked on Gaming tournament smart contracts and Backend api to interact with the application.
- At the forefront of Metaverse Gaming innovation, my passion converges on sculpting a groundbreaking Game Tournaments and NFT marketplace, primed for airdrop excellence. My dedication unfolds in expanding the platform's horizons, imbuing it with the prowess of ICO integration, NFT Rental, Staking, and Swapping meticulously tailored for the gaming realm.

Sr.Blockchain developer | Calsoft

Jul 2023 - present

- Working with Senior blockchain team and Worked on Gaming tournament smart contracts and Backend api to interact with the application.
- At the forefront of Metaverse Gaming innovation, my passion converges on sculpting a groundbreaking Game Tournaments and NFT marketplace, primed for airdrop excellence. My dedication unfolds in expanding the platform's horizons, imbuing it with the prowess of ICO integration, NFT Rental, Staking, and Swapping meticulously tailored for the gaming realm.

TECHNICAL SKILLS_

Programming Development and Databases Tools Solidity, JavaScript, Node.js, Nest.js, Typescript, Rainbow-Kit, Ether.js, Web3.js ExpressJS, ReactJS, MongoDB Git, GitHub, VSCode